A Guide to the Works Projects Administration of Virginia Records, 1939-1943
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Works Projects Administration of Virginia Records, 1939-1943
The Library of Virginia
30432
186.55 cubic feet (554 boxes)
Works Projects Administration of Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
THE COLLECTION IS LOCATED AT THE STATE RECORDS CENTER. CONTACT ARCHIVES RESEARCH SERVICES FOR ACCESS INFORMATION, DIRECTIONS, AND HOURS.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the Archives at an unknown date, 21 April 1979.
Historical Information
The Works Projects Administration (known as the Works Progress Administration until 1 July 1939) was established by an Executive Order of 6 May 1935, as the agency responsible for the execution of the Government's work-relief program as a whole. Before this the Federal Government had participated in the relief program through the Federal Emergency Relief Administration (FERA), set up under an act of 12 May 1933, and the Civil Works Administration, established by an Executive order of 9 November 1933, the two agencies having a common administrator. With the abolition of the Civil Works Administration in March 1934, the records of the agency were transferred to the Emergency Work Relief Program of the FERA, which continued in existence until December 1935. The administration of work relief, however, was taken over by the WPA when that agency was created in May 1935. Under the President's Reorganization Plan No. I, effective on 1 July 1939, the WPA was made part of the Federal Works Agency. The WPA was officially abolished on 30 June 1943.
The WPA in Virginia constructed roads, such as the Blue Ridge Parkway and buildings on college campuses. The WPA also created jobs for those with other talents such as writers, who were put to work completing surveys of Historical Records of the Commonwealth and collecting the life histories of Virginians, including ones who formerly had been slaves.
Scope and Content
The following is a preliminary inventory and finding aid. The collection is not fully processed but is available at the State Records Center. Records, 1939-1943, of the Works Projects Administration of Virginia documenting it's efforts to provide relief jobs for artists, musicians, actors, and white-collar and professional workers during the Great Depression. While many jobs created by the federal government during this period were primarily construction work, repair work, and other manual labor jobs, the WPA also established federal art, music, theater and writers' projects to provide relief jobs for unemployed clerks, writers, editors, lawyers, teachers, librarians, and similar workers. This collection contains various surveys and writing projects such as oral histories, abstracts and transcripts of court records, published books, radio plays, and state histories. Of note are the Virginia Writers' Project Life Histories, which recorded the life stories of men and women from a variety of regions, occupations, and ethnic groups and include over 300 slave narratives. Also of note are the Historical Records Survey, Virginia Historical Inventory, a collection of photographs, maps, and detailed reports documenting the architectural, cultural, and family histories of thousands of 18th- and 19th-century buildings in communities across Virginia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Historical Records Survey
II. Virginia Writers' Project
III. Clipping Files
IV. Photographs
V. Miscellaneous Files
Contents List
- Series I. Historical Records Survey.
  This series consists of seven subseries: 1. Inventories of Counties and Cities; 2. Inventories of State; 3. Church Records; 4. Production Files; 5. Court Abstracts and Transcripts; 6. Miscellaneous Programs; and 7. Virginia Historical Inventory.
  - Subseries 1. Inventories of Counties and Cities.
    Consists of survey forms describing types of information and records stored at county and city municipal offices, including chancery dockets, clerk minute books and daybooks.
    Arranged alphabetically with counties listed first and then independent cities.
    - Counties of Accomack-Albemarle. (Box 1)
    - County of Albemarle. (Box 2)
    - Counties of Alleghany-Amherst. (Box 3)
    - Counties of Amherst-Arlington. (Box 4)
    - Counties of Arlington-Augusta. (Box 5)
    - Counties of Augusta-Bland. (Box 6)
    - Counties of Botetourt-Brunswick. (Box 7)
    - Counties of Buckingham-Caroline. (Box 8)
    - Counties of Caroline-Clarke. (Box 9)
    - Counties of Clarke-Culpeper. (Box 10)
    - Counties of Culpeper-Dickenson. (Box 11)
    - Counties of Elizabeth City-Fairfax. (Box 12)
    - Counties of Fauquier-Franklin. (Box 13)
    - Counties of Franklin-Grayson. (Box 14)
    - Counties of Grayson-Halifax. (Box 15)
    - Counties of Halifax-Hanover. (Box 16)
    - Counties of Hanover-Henrico. (Box 17)
    - Counties of Henrico-Henry. (Box 18)
    - Counties of Henry-James City.
    - Counties of James City-Lancaster. (Box 20)
    - Counties of Lee-Louisa. (Box 21)
    - Counties of Louisa -Montgomery. (Box 22)
    - County of Nansemond. (Box 23)
    - Counties of Nansemond-Nelson. (Box 24)
    - County of New Kent. (Box 25)
    - Counties of New Kent-Norfolk. (Box 26)
    - Counties of Norfolk-Nottoway. (Box 27)
    - Counties of Page-Pittsylvania. (Box 28)
    - Counties of Pittsylvania-Prince Edward. (Box 29)
    - Counties of Prince Edward-Princess Anne. (Box 30)
    - Counties of Pulaski-Rappahannock. (Box 31)
    - Counties of Richmond-Roanoke. (Box 32)
    - Counties of Roanoke-Rockingham. (Box 33)
    - County of Rockingham. (Box 34-35)
    - Counties of Rockingham-Scott. (Box 36)
    - Counties of Shenandoah-Smythe. (Box 37)
    - Counties of Southampton-Tazewell. (Box 38)
    - Counties of Tazewell-Warwick. (Box 39)
    - County of Warwick. (Box 40)
    - Counties of Warwick-Washington. (Box 41)
    - Counties of Washington-Westmoreland. (Box 42)
    - Counties of Westmoreland-Wise. (Box 43)
    - Counties of Wise-York. (Box 44)
    - Municipalities of Abingdon-Danville. (Box 45)
    - Municipalities of Danville-Hampton. (Box 46)
    - Municipalities of Harrisonburg-Lynchburg. (Box 47)
    - Municipalities of Lynchburg-Newport News. (Box 48)
    - Municipality of Norfolk. (Box 49)
    - Municipalities of Norfolk-Portsmouth. (Box 50)
    - Municipalities of Portsmouth-Richmond. (Box 51)
    - Municipality of Richmond. (Box 52)
    - Municipalities of Richmond-Roanoke. (Box 53)
    - Municipalities of Roanoke-Staunton. (Box 54)
    - Municipalities of Suffolk-Wise. (Box 55)
    - Municipality of Rockingham. (Box 56-58)
    - Municipalities of Russell-Scott. (Box 59)
    - Municipalities of Scott-Shenandoah. (Box 60)
  - Subseries 2. Inventories of State.
    Consists of survey forms detailing types of records found at various Virginia state offices, including the State Library of Virginia.
    - Inventories, State. (Box 61-64)
    - Inventories, Miscellaneous. (Box 549-550)
  - Subseries 3. Church Records.
    Consists of notes on churches in Virginia, detailing the history of the church, types of records at the church, and physical description of the church.
    - Church Records, Episcopal. (Box 102-111)
    - Church Records, Presbyterian. (Box 112)
    - Church Records. (Box 113-117)
    - Church Records-Historical Facts, miscellaneous 5x8 cards. (Box 118-121)
  - Subseries 4. Production Files.
    Consists of rough drafts of entries for work forms and research notes from counties.
    - County of Essex. (Box 260-266)
    - County of Pittsylvania. (Box 267-276)
    - County of King William. (Box 277)
    - Counties of King William and Halifax. (Box 278)
    - County of Halifax. (Box 279-284)
    - Counties of Halifax and Prince William. (Box 285)
    - County of Prince William. (Box 286-291)
    - County of Norfolk. (Box 292-293)
    - County of Princess Anne. (Box 294-296)
    - County Archives, Legal Research. (Box 297-302)
    - County Archives, Legal Research and Vital Statistics. (Box 303)
    - County Archives, Vital Statistics. (Box 304-306)
    - Imprints. (Box 307-344)
  - Subseries 5. Court Abstracts and Transcripts.
    Consists of abstracts and transcripts of court records, including minute books and order books.
    - County of Amelia, 1735-1763. (Box 397)
      Includes Order Book 1, 1735-1746 through Order Book 7, 1763.
    - County of Amelia, 1764-1778. (Box 398)
      Includes Order Book 8, 1764-1765 through Order Book _, 1776-1778.
    - County of Amelia, 1780-1804. (Box 399)
      Order Book 15, 1780-1782 through Order Book 24, 1800-1804. (Order Book 16 is missing)
    - County of Amelia, 1801-1828. (Box 400)
      Order Book 25, 1801-1802 through Order Book 35, 1827-1828.
    - County of Amelia, 1828-1837. (Box 401)
      Order Book 36, 1828-1829 through Order Book 39, 1834-1837.
    - County of Arlington, 1847-1852. (Box 402)
      Minutes County Court 2, 1847-1852.
    - County of Arlington, 1847-1855. (Box 403)
      Minutes County Court 2, 1847-1852 and Minutes County Court 3, 1852-1855.
    - County of Arlington, 1855-1858. (Box 404)
      Minutes County Court 4, 1855-1858.
    - County of Arlington, 1858-1862. (Box 405)
      Minute Book 5, 1858-1862.
    - County of Arlington, 1858-1862. (Box 406)
      Index to Minute Book 5, 1858-1862 through miscellaneous records.
    - County of Bedford, 1754-1771. (Box 407)
      Order Book I-A, 1754-1758 through Order Book III, 1763-1771
    - County of Bedford, 1763-1771. (Box 408)
      Order Book III, 1763-1771.
    - County of Buckingham, 1870-1928. (Box 409)
      Supervisors Minute Books, 1870-1928 through Order Books, 1870-1892.
    - County of Carroll, 1842-1846. (Box 410)
      Order Book I-A, 1842-1843 through Order Book 1, 1842-1843.
    - County of Carroll, 1842-1852. (Box 411)
      Order Book 1, 1842-1846 through Order Book 2, 1847-1852.
    - County of Carroll, 1847-1857. (Box 412)
      Order Book 2, 1847-1852 through Order Book 4, 1852-1857. (Order Book 3 missing)
    - County of Carroll, 1852-1857. (Box 413)
      Order Book 4, 1852-1857.
    - County of Charles City, 1860-1872. (Box 414)
      Order Book, 1860-1872.
    - County of Charles City, 1860-1872. (Box 415)
    - County of Clarke, 1836-1845. (Box 416)
      Order Book A, 1836-1845.
    - County of Craig, 1851-1860. (Box 417)
      Order Book, 1851-1860.
    - County of Craig, 1851-1876. (Box 418)
      Order Book, 1851-1860 through Order Book, 1865-1876.
    - County of Craig, 1865-1888. (Box 419)
      Order Book, 1865-1876 through Order Book 2, 1877-1888.
    - County of Craig, 1877-1888. (Box 420)
      Order Book 2, 1877-1888.
    - County of Cumberland, 1749-1758. (Box 421)
      Order Book, 1749-1751 through Order Book, 1752-1758.
    - County of Dickenson, 1880-1896. (Box 422)
      Chancery Order Book, 1881-1896 through Law Order Book 1, 1880-1884.
    - County of Dickenson, 1880-1888. (Box 423)
      Law Order Book 1, 1880-1884 through Law Order Book 2, 1884-1888.
    - County of Dickenson, 1884-1891. (Box 424)
      Law Order Book 2, 1884-1888 through Law Order Book 3, 1888-1891.
    - County of Dinwiddie, 1855-1863. (Box 425)
      Order Book 2, 1858-1863 and Minute Book 1, 1855-1858.
    - County of Dinwiddie, 1832-1938. (Box 426)
      Order Book 2-8, 1858-1904; Chancery Order Book 1-3, 1832-1883; Chancery Order Book 2-4, 1918-1938; Order Book 2, 1873-1909; Minute Book 1, 1855-1858; Fiduciary Record, 1856-1897, 1904-1918; Supervisors Record 1-3, 1870-1938; Order Book 1-6, 1909-1938; Abstracts.
    - County of Fairfax, 1749. (Box 427)
      Order Book, 1734-1749
    - County of Fairfax, 1754-1772. (Box 428)
      Order Book, 1770-1772 and Orders, 1754-1756.
    - County of Fairfax, 1783-1792. (Box 429)
      Order Book, 1783-1788; Order Book, 1788-1792 (incomplete) and Index A-W.
    - County of Greenville, 1781-1789. (Box 430)
      Order Book, 1781-1789.
    - County of Greenville, 1781-1858. (Box 431)
      Order Book 1-12, 1781-1858; Order 2, 1790-1799 and abstracts.
    - County of Halifax, 1752-1763. (Box 432)
      Index; Plea Books 1-4, 1752-1763 and Plea Book 2, 1755-1759.
    - County of Halifax, 1755-1762. (Box 433)
      Index: Plea Book 2 1755-1759 and Plea Book 3, 1759-1762.
    - County of Halifax, 1759-1762. (Box 434)
      Plea Book 3, 1759-1762.
    - County of Halifax, 1763-1767. (Box 435)
      Plea Book 4, 1763-1764 and Plea Book 5, 1764-1767.
    - County of Halifax, 1767-1770. (Box 436)
      Plea Book 6, 1767-1770 and Index.
    - County of Halifax, 1770-1773. (Box 437)
      Plea Book 6 and Plea Book 7, 1770-1773.
    - County of Halifax, 1773-1774. (Box 438)
      Plea Book 8, 1773-1774.
    - County of Hanover, 1809-1896. (Box 439)
      Abstracts, 1809-1896.
    - County of Henrico, 1784-1789. (Box 440)
      Order Book 2, 1784-1787 and Order Book 3, 1787-1789.
    - County of Henrico, 1781-1812. (Box 441)
      Order Books 1-3, 1781-1789; Order Books 12-18, 1805-1812; Minute Books, 1789-1792; Minute book, 1792-1795; Minute Book, 1793-1795; Minute Book, 1803-1806 and abstracts.
    - County of Henry, 1777-1791. (Box 442)
      Order Book 1, 1777-1778; Order Book 2, 1778-1782; Order Book 3, 1782-1785; Order Book 4, 1785-1788; Order Book 5, 1788-1791.
    - County of Henry, 1792-1804. (Box 443)
      Order Book 6, 1792-1797 and Order Book 7 1797-1804.
    - County of Henry, 1804-1820. (Box 444)
      Order Book 8, 1804-1808; Order Book 9, 1808-1811 and Order Book 10, 1811-1820.
    - County of King and Queen, 1858-1871. (Box 445)
      Minute Books, 1858-1866 and Minute Books, 1866-1871.
    - County of King and Queen, 1871-1877. (Box 446)
      Minute Book, 1871-1877 and Index.
    - County of King and Queen, 1877-1888. (Box 447)
      Minute Book, 1877-1882 and Minute Book, 1883-1888.
    - County of King William, 1677-1895. (Box 448)
      Record Book 1, 1677-1895, Record Book 1, 1702-1707, Record Book 2, 1702-1786, Record Book 3, 1793-1800, Record Book 4, 1711-1805, Record Book 5, 1806-1810, Law Order Book, 1889-1892, and County Court Orders Book 3, 1892-1895.
    - County of King William, 1811-1889. (Box 449)
      Order Book 3, Minute Book 1, 1885-1889, and Record Book 6, 1811-1816.
    - County of Lee, 1808-1904. (Box 450)
      Law Order Book 1, 1808-1811, Order Book 1, 1831-1847, Order Book 2, 1843-1854, Law Order Book 2, 1814-1819, and List of Law Order Books, 1808-1904.
    - County of Lee, 1814-1834. (Box 451)
      Order Book 2, 1814-1819, Law Order Book 3, 1826-1834.
    - County of Loudoun, 1757-1773. (Box 452)
      Order Book A, 1757-1762, Order Book B, 1762-1765, Order Book C, 1765-1767, Order Book D, 1767-1769, and Order Book E, 1770-1773.
    - County of Loudoun, 1762-1767. (Box 453)
      Order Book B, 1762-1765 and Order Book C, 1765-1767.
    - County of Montgomery, 1773-1786. (Box 454)
      Order Book 1, 1773-1786.
    - County of Montgomery. (Box 455)
      Order Book 2 and pages of index.
    - County of Montgomery. (Box 456)
      Order Book 2 through Order Book 4.
    - County of Montgomery, 1772-1793. (Box 457)
      Order Book 1, 1772-1788, Order Book 2, 1774, Order Book 3, 1779, Order Book 5, 1790-1791 and Order Book 6, 1792-1793.
    - Counties of Nansemond and Northumberland, 1807-1904. (Box 458)
      Nansemond Law Order Book 1, 1885 and Order Book 1, 1866-1871. Northumberland Abstracts, Law Order Book, 1861-1904, Supervisor's Book 1-3, 1807-1902.
    - County of Page, 1831-1844. (Box 459)
      Order Book 1, 1831-1838 and Order Book 2, 1838-1844.
    - County of Page, 1844-1854. (Box 460)
      Minute Book 3, 1844-1850 and Minute Book 4, 1850-1854.
    - County of Page, 1831-1868. (Box 461)
      Minute Book 4, 1850-1854, Minute Book 5, 1855-1861, Minute Book 6, 1862-1868, Order 1, 1831-1838, Order Book 2, 1838-1844, and Order Book 3, 1844-1850.
    - County of Pittsylvania, 1767-1772. (Box 462)
      Court Records 1, Court Records, 1767-1772, and index.
    - County of Pittslyvania, 1772-1775. (Box 463)
      Court Records and Orders 2, 1772-1775
    - County of Pittsylvania. (Box 464)
      Court Records 2.
    - County of Pittsylvania, 1776-1791. (Box 465)
      Court Records 3, 1776-1791 and Court Records 4, 1777-1783.
    - County of Pittsylvania, 1777-1783. (Box 466)
      Court Records 4, 1777-1783 and Court Records 5, 1783-1787.
    - County of Pittsylvania, 1783-1787. (Box 467)
      Court Records 5, 1783-1787
    - County of Pittsylvania, 1767-1905. (Box 468)
      Order Book 1, 1767-1772, Order Book 1 1787-1791, Order Books 2-13, 1772-1809, Judgement Lein Docket and Execution Books 2, 1889-1905, Index, and miscellaneous list of clerk's records.
    - County of Powhatan, 1777-1814. (Box 469)
      Order Books 1-11, 1777-1814.
    - County of Powhatan, 1814-1816. (Box 470)
      Order Book 12, 1814-1816.
    - County of Prince William, 1752-1839. (Box 471)
      Order Books 1-6, 1752-1839.
    - County of Prince William, 1761-1806. (Box 472)
      Order Book 4, 1761-1763, Order Book 5, 1766-1769, and Order Book 7, 1804-1806.
    - County of Prince William, 1794-1807. (Box 473)
      District Court Order Book, 1794-1798 and District Court Order Book 8, 1804-1807.
    - County of Prince William. (Box 474)
      District Court Order Book 8.
    - County of Pulaski. (Box 475)
      County Court Order Books 1-12 and Circuit Court Order Books 1-4.
    - County of Pulaski. (Box 476)
      Circuit Court Order Books 5-9.
    - County of Pulaski, 1870-1898. (Box 477)
      Circuit Court Order Books 10-11, Circuit Court Chancery Orders 1-2, Minute Book 1, Supervisor's Order Book 1, 1870-1893 and 1885-1898.
    - County of Pulaski, 1893-1925. (Box 478)
      Supervisor's Order Book 1, 1904-1906, Supervisor's Order Book 2, 1893-1911, Supervisor's Order Book 3, 1911-1925 and 1898-1904, Supervisor's Order Books 4-5 and records.
    - County of Pulaski, 1871-1929. (Box 479)
      Minutes of Board of Supervisors Settlements, 1871-1825, Road Accounts, 1906-1919, and Supervisors Road Order Books, 1920-1929.
    - County of Rappahannock, 1833-1840. (Box 480)
      Minute Book A, 1833-1836, and Minute Book B, 1836-1840.
    - County of Rappahannock, 1840-1847. (Box 481)
      Minute Book C, 1840-1843 and Minute Book D, 1843-1847.
    - County of Rappahannock. (Box 482)
      Minute Book E.
    - County of Rappahannock, 1852-1862. (Box 483)
      Minute Book F, 1852-1856, index, Minute Book G, 1856-1862.
    - County of Rappahannock. (Box 484)
      Minute Book I, M, and N, Common Law Order Books A-G, and Supervisor's Minute Book 1-4.
    - County of Richmond, 1692-1825. (Box 485)
      Order Books 1-26, 1692-1825.
    - County of Richmond, 1825-1881. (Box 486)
      Order Books 27-32, 1825-1881.
    - County of Richmond, 1857-1937. (Box 487)
      Order Books 33-34, 1882-1904, Record Book of Board of Supervisors, 1870-1837, Circuit Court Order Book, 1857-1927, and Records of Local Board of Review.
    - County of Russell, 1786-1838. (Box 488)
      Law Order Books 1-10, 1786-1838.
    - County of Russell, 1853-1897. (Box 489)
      Order Books 11-21, 1853-1890 and Order Books 22-23, 1890-1897.
    - County of Russell, 1831-1919. (Box 490)
      Chancery Order Book 1, 1831-1872, Law Order Books 24-25, 1897-1904, Supervisors Order Book 1, 1871-1897, and Supervisors Order Books 3-5, 1897-1919.
    - County of Scott, 1815-1832. (Box 491)
      Order Book 1, 1815-1819, Order Book 2, 1819-1824, Order Book 3, 1824-1828, Order Book 4, 1828-1832, and List of Law Order Books.
    - County of Scott, 1819-1824. (Box 492)
      Order Book 2, 1819-1824.
    - County of Scott. (Box 493)
      Order Book 2.
    - County of Scott, 1819-1828. (Box 494)
      Order Book 2, 1819-1824 and Order Book 3, 1824-1828.
    - County of Scott, 1824-1832. (Box 495)
      Order Book 3, 1824-1828 and Order Book 4, 1828-1832.
    - County of Scott, 1828-1832. (Box 496)
      Order Book 4, 1828-1832.
    - County of Shenandoah, 1772-1800. (Box 497)
      Minute Book, 1774-1780, Minute Book, 1785-1788, Minute Book, 1791-1796, Minute Book 1798-1800, and Order Book 1772-1774.
    - County of Shenandoah, 1781-1798. (Box 498)
      Order Book, 1781-1784, Order Book 1784-1786, and Order Book 1795-1798.
    - County of Southampton, 1759-1824. (Box 500)
      Order Books 1759-1824.
    - County of Southampton, 1793-1843. (Box 501)
      Order Books, 1835-1843 and Minute Books, 1793-1835.
    - County of Spotsylvania, 1724-1774. (Box 502)
      Order Book, 1724-1730, Order Book, 1730-1738, and Order Book, 1768-1774.
    - County of Spotsylvania, 1774-1831. (Box 503)
      Order Book, 1774-1782, Order Book 1, 1782-1786, and Order Book, 1809-1831.
    - County of Spotsylvania, 1786-1789. (Box 504)
      Minute Book, 1786-1789.
    - County of Tazewell, 1821-1846. (Box 505)
      Order Books, 1809-1846, Minute Books, 1821-1831, Circuit Court Order Books, 1832-1844, Circuit Court Order Books, 1825-1831.
    - County of Tazewell, 1831-1841. (Box 506)
      Minute Book, 1831-1841
    - County of Tazewell, 1840-1849. (Box 507)
      Special Terms-Minutes of County Court, 1840-1849.
    - County of Warren, 1836-1855. (Box 508)
      Common Law Orders A, 1836-1855 and Minute Book A, 1836-1844.
    - County of Warren, 1836-1853. (Box 509)
      Minute Book A, County Court, 1836-1844, Minute Book B, County Court, 1844-1853.
    - County of Wise, 1856-1883. (Box 510)
      Order Books 1-3, 7 and 8, 1856-1883.
    - County of Wise, 1863-1888. (Box 511)
      Order Book 7, 1885-1888 and Order Book, 1863-1867.
    - County of Wise, 1885-1888. (Box 512)
      Order book 7, 1885-1888.
    - County of Wise, 1885-1889. (Box 513)
      Order Book 7, 1885-1888 and Order Book 8, 1888-1889.
    - County of Wise, 1888-1889. (Box 514)
      Order Book 8, 1888-1889.
    - County of Wise, 1889-1891. (Box 515)
      Order Book 9, 1889-1891.
    - County of Wythe, 1790-1900. (Box 516)
      Minute Books, 1790-1805 and Order Books, 1790-1900.
    - County of Wythe, 1790-1805. (Box 517)
      Minute Books, 1790-1805.
    - County of Wythe County, 1799-1808. (Box 518)
      Order Book, 1799-1801 and Order Book, 1805-1808.
    - County of Wythe, 1809-1812. (Box 519)
      Order Books, 1809-1812
    - County of Wythe, 1812-1815. (Box 520)
      Order Book, 1812-1815.
    - Fredericksburg City, 1781-1804. (Box 521)
      Order Book D, 1801-1804, Hastings Court Law Book A, 1781-1785, District Court law Order Book A, 1789-1793, District Court Law Order Book B, 1794-1798, District Court Law Order Book C, 1799-1801.
    - Fredericksburg City, 1804-1806. (Box 522)
      District Court Order Book, 1804-1806.
    - Fredericksburg City, 1807-1811. (Box 523)
      Order Book F, 1807-1811.
    - Lynchburg City, 1867-1886. (Box 524)
      Chancery Orders 1-5, 1867-1886.
    - Lynchburg City, 1889-1898. (Box 525)
      Chancery Orders 7, 1889-1892 and Chancery Orders 9, 1895-1898.
    - Lynchburg City, 1898-1922. (Box 526)
      Chancery Orders 10-15, 1898-1922.
    - Lynchburg City, 1812-1913. (Box 527)
      Hustings Court Order Book, 1812-1817, Corporation Court Law Orders, 1868-1872, Corporation Court Law Orders, 1874-1913.
    - Lynchburg City, 1903-1924. (Box 528)
      Corporation Court Law Order Books 19-27, 1903-1924.
    - Lynchburg City, 1924-1938. (Box 529)
      Corporation Court Law Order Books 28-33, 1924-1938.
    - Lynchburg City, 1823-1939. (Box 530)
      Circuit-Superior Court Law Order Books 1-15, 1823-1939
    - Richmond City, 1793-1870. (Box 531)
      Hustings Court Minute Books 1-31, 1793-1870.
    - Richmond City, 1782-1879. (Box 532)
      Hustings Court Order Books 1-13, 1782-1817, Common Law Order Books, 1-7, 1860-1870, Hustings Court Order Books 1-10, 1870-1879.
    - Richmond City, 1879-1901. (Box 533)
      Hustings Court Order Books 11-38, 1879-1901.
    - Richmond City, 1901-1910. (Box 534)
      Hustings Court Order Books 39-51, 1901-1910.